Whether you memorize a script or read from one,
or use a few notes, or don't use any
notes at all, a talk that is
well prepared and passionately delivered will always impact
an audience.
But what does delivering a talk passionately look like?
It's time to find your voice.
Here's a radical question.
Why bother to give a talk?
Why not simply email the script
to every potential member of the audience?
One of the special things about TED is
that it shows how talks can offer something more
than printed words.
But that doesn't just happen automatically.
Not every talk offers something extra.
That something extra has to be
thought about, invested in, and developed.
It has to be earned.
What is that something extra?
It's our humanity.
Our humanity turns information into inspiration.
Here are some of the things the
human layer can bring to a text.
I trust this person.
Every sentence sounds so interesting.
I hear it in your voice
and see it in your face.
The emphasis on that word with that hand gesture?
Now I get it.
Empathy.
I can tell how much that hurt you.
Excitement.
Wow, that passion is infectious.
Conviction.
Such determination in those eyes.
Action.
I want to be on your team.
Sign me up.
Together, these things create inspiration.
We think of inspiration as the force that tells
the brain what to do with a new idea.
Many of us are inspired by the idea of inspiration.
We think of inspiration as the force that tells
the brain what to do with a new idea.
Many of us are inspired by the idea of inspiration.
Many ideas just get filed away and probably soon forgotten.
Inspiration, on the other hand, sets
off our mind's attention alert system.
There are two major things to consider
when preparing a talk for an audience.
The first is, what am I doing with my voice?
And the second is, what
am I doing with my body?
Speak with meaning.
Listen to the opening minute of
the TED Talk by George Monbiot.
When I was a young man, I spent six
years of wild adventure in the tropics working as
an investigative journalist in some of
the most bewitching part of the world.
I was as reckless and foolish as only young
men can be, this is why wars get fought.
But I also felt more
alive than I've ever done since.
And when I came home, I found the
scope of my existence gradually diminishing until loading
the dishwasher seemed like an interesting challenge.
And I found that I have power.
I found myself sort of
scratching at the walls of life,
as if I was trying to find a way out
into a wider space beyond.
I was, I believe, ecologically bored.
When you hear Monbiot speak,
you find yourself pulled into his world.
He uses his voice in a way that adds meaning
to every word he says.
That's something you wouldn't get
if you read his script in a book.
His words are interesting,
but it's the way he says them
that gives his audience a feeling
of curiosity and astonishment.
How does he do this?
The key to being an exciting speaker
is to create variety in the way you speak.
Variety based on the meaning you're trying to get across.
So many speakers forget this.
They give a talk in
which every sentence sounds the same,
with a slight rise at the
start and a drop at the end.
There are no pauses or changes of pace.
This communicates that no single part of a talk
matters more than any other part.
It's just the same thing over
and over again until the end.
Listening to a talk like
this can feel like being hypnotized.
That is, it puts an audience to sleep.
If your talk is scripted, try this.
Find the most important two
or three words in each sentence
and underline them.
Then look for the one word in each paragraph
that really matters,
and underline them.
Underline it twice.
If there are bits that are lighthearted or playful,
run a wavy pencil line under those.
Look for every question mark and highlight it
with a yellow highlighter.
Find the single biggest aha moment in the whole talk
and put a great big black blob right before it.
If there's a joke or a funny story,
put little pink dots above it.
Now, try reading your script, making
sure to change your voice in response to each mark.
For example, let yourself laugh a little
while looking at the pink dots.
Pause for the big black blob.
And speed up a bit for the wavy pencil line.
Or speak more softly.
How does that sound?
Now try one more thing.
Remember all the emotions associated
with each section of your talk.
Which bits are you most passionate about?
Which issues make you angry?
What makes you laugh?
What confuses you?
Read your talk again, letting those emotions out
a little as you speak.
Try doing this with a friend.
See what she responds to or
what she rolls her eyes at.
Record yourself reading your talk,
then play it back with your eyes closed.
How's it sounding?
Don't struggle to add variety to your voice
when that doesn't feel right to you.
Let it come naturally from the passion you feel
for your idea.
You want to sound like yourself, expressing curiosity
and excitement when it's appropriate.
You know the voice you use when you're catching up
with friends or family members
you haven't seen in a while?
That's the kind of voice you'll want to use
to present your talk.
Real, natural, and unafraid to let it rip
if what you're saying demands it.
It's important to use your body, too.
Sometimes, a speaker will give the impression
that his body is only there to carry his thoughts.
It's important to carry his head onto the stage.
Once in front of the
audience, the body no longer knows
what to do with itself.
It stands awkwardly, hands glued to its side,
or sways back and forth
from one leg to the other.
But there are a few things you can think about
that may help you feel more comfortable on stage
and make you seem more confident to your audience.
The simplest way to present a talk powerfully
is just to stand tall.
Put equal weight on both your feet,
keeping your feet a few inches apart.
Use your hands and arms to naturally emphasize
whatever it is you're saying.
This is enough to signal
to the audience that you're calm
and that you know what you're talking about.
This is the method used
by a majority of TED speakers.
The key is to feel relaxed
and to let your upper body move freely.
Good posture helps.
Avoid slouching your shoulders forward.
Standing so openly may feel vulnerable,
but that vulnerability can be
nice for an audience to see.
Some speakers prefer to walk the stage.
It helps them think.
It helps them emphasize key moments,
and this is important,
they frequently stop to dwell on important points.
It's that change in rhythm
that makes the walking method work.
Constant pacing without a change in rhythm
can be tiring to watch.
But pacing, broken up, and relaxed,
can be a great way to relax.
But by moments of stillness can be powerful.
Something to avoid is nervously shifting from leg to leg.
Or walking forward and back a couple of steps
in a kind of rocking motion.
Many speakers do this without realizing it.
They may be feeling a little anxious
and shifting from one leg
to the other eases their discomfort.
But from the audience's point of view,
it actually highlights that discomfort.
The difference between a speaker who rocks
back and forth and a speaker who finds stillness
can be huge for an audience.
So move if you want to,
but only move if you can move with purpose.
Then when you want to emphasize a point,
stop moving and address your audience
from a stance of calm power.
There are plenty of other ways
you can speak with power too.
Dame Stephanie Shirley chose to sit for her talk,
using a metal stool with one
foot tucked back on a run,
and notes in her lap.
It looked relaxed and natural.
The late great neurologist Oliver Sacks
also sat for his talk.
Clifford Stoll leapt and darted around the stage
with such energy it added an entirely new
and unique flavor to his talk.
So there are no rules.
You just have to find
a way of being on stage
that makes you feel comfortable and confident,
and that doesn't distract from what you're saying.
The simple test is to rehearse
in front of a small audience
and ask them if your body language
is getting in the way of your message.
Or record yourself speaking and watch it back
to see if you're doing anything
you didn't know you were doing with your body.
There's a place in the world
for all types of presentation styles.
Just make sure your body knows
it's not just there to carry your head around.
It's allowed to enjoy its time on stage.
Do it your way.
Don't try to be someone else.
Focus on your idea and your passion for it.
And don't be afraid to
let your own personality shine through.
This is one of the first
steps in forming a trusting bond
with your audience, which is exactly what we focus on
in our next video.
Check it out.
ご視聴ありがとうございました